# Miguel Ramos

# Full Stack Developer

Vancouver, WA

360-980-0308 | drexelramos@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

## **OBJECTIVE**

Self-motivated and accomplished business professional with over 10 years of experience within sales and financial services industry. Helped develop ecommerce website for cannabis company which processes over \$1.2M in sales annually. Looking to leverage extensive background in sales, problem-solving and effective communication into a new career as a Full Stack Developer.

## **SKILLS**

Front End	Back End	Additional Tools/Skills	<b>Professional Skills</b>
HTML5   CSS3   Sass jQuery   JavaScript ES6 React   React Hooks   JSX Bootstrap   Materialize	Node.js   MongoDB PostgreSQL   Express	Git   GitHub   npm Postman   Enzyme WordPress   Airtable RESTful APIs	Problem-Solving Critical Thinking Creativity   Teamwork Effective Communication

## **PROJECTS**

## Heavenly Buds | Live Site Link

- Collaborated to create ordering website for cannabis company increasing sales 140%
- Conceptualized custom design to reflect company branding and image
- Developed wireframes for improved UI/UX and logical website navigation. Coding done by freelancer
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | WordPress

#### Stocks Analysis | Project Link | GitHub

- Thinkful API project
- Designed & created application to retrieve a company's financial & stock information from multiple APIs
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | RESTful APIs

## Omnifood | Project Link | GitHub

- Udemy project
- SPA for food delivery company utilizing JavaScript and CSS techniques
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Developer

## Freelance | Vancouver, WA (remote)

January 2021 - Present

September 2019 - Present

- Web development for small businesses & non-profits
- Develop UI/UX strategies including wireframes and mockups
- Design, code & create websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

## Account Manager

## American Fidelity | Portland, OR (remote)

Achieved multiple insurance & investment licenses - Life, Health, Series 63, Series 6

- Analyze financial and personal data to create customized health and retirement plans
- Tested multiple applications to develop contingency processes during COVID-19 pandemic contributing to the highest sales performance ever by the region
- Utilize Salesforce as a CRM, online scheduling tool, ordering for marketing materials and customer service center

## Territory Sales Manager

#### Kornerstone Credit | Seattle, WA (remote)

August 2018 - September 2019

- Exceptional performance selling alternative financing options to auto repair shops and furniture retailers utilizing consultative solutions-based sales approach
- Helped grow this startup company from \$0 to over \$6 million in monthly company funding
- Successfully grew regional merchant partner base from 0 to over 120 locations
- Executed user testing on lending application to simplify transaction processing and increase loan approval rates

#### **Property Manager**

#### CM3 Real Estate | Vancouver, WA (remote)

May 2017 - November 2018

- Negotiated, purchased and sold real estate in multiple states
- Developed ecommerce site for selling real estate which decreased days on market by 50%
- Created SPA for purchasing real estate and implemented processes for automating the screening procedure of sellers increasing efficiency and scalability and decreasing phone time by 8 hours per week
- Created videos and digital marketing campaigns across many social media platforms and industry channels

## **Territory Sales Executive**

#### Western Union | Seattle, WA (remote)

September 2005 - May 2017

- Received multiple awards for exceptional Teamwork and Sales results President's Club, Achiever Award, Driven Award, MVP Award
- Achieved profit increases ranging from 5% 18% per customer through renegotiation of money transfer contracts
- Conducted user testing on money transfer desktop and mobile applications resulting in better UX, increased revenue and 15% higher app utilization within existing customers
- Trained 12 new employees on sales techniques, Compliance and Anti-Money Laundering policies and procedures
- Utilized Salesforce as a CRM and troubleshooting customer service tickets

#### **EDUCATION**

## B.A. in Computer Science & Information Science

**Drexel University** 

Minored: Business & Mathematics

#### Software Engineering

#### **Thinkful**

• Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on full stack mobile-first applications, algorithms and data structures